Hello I'm Georgie and I'm Phil We to Real easyy English Find all the vocabulary and a worksheet to test what you've learned over on our website go tobblearningenglish.com. .
Hi, Phil, how are you doing I'm doing really well, Georgie, I must say your hair is looking fantastic today.
Thank you very much, Phil today we are talking about hair.
Now I can see your hair but for our listeners maybe you can start by describing your hair Okay,
Well my hair it's it's short but it's not very short I think it's fairly straight and then,
The colour, it's kind of a light brown colour, the bits that aren't grey.
That is you said your hair used to be ginger, Yes, it used to be ginger, bright orange, wow.
Well my hair is naturally dark brown, it's quite short and it's wavy, so sometimes it can be curly, but mostly it's wavy.
Okay, so you you've told us about your hair, Georgie, do you like it, Yes, I do now I actually when I was younger, I didn't really like my hair because.
I wanted it to be straight, so I used to straighten it to take the curls and the waves out,
But as I've got older I've started to really like my hair, it looks a bit wild and I enjoy it.
What about you, How do you do you like your hair, Yeah, usually I do, I think similar to you when I was a teenager,
I just wanted my hair to look different, so I used to try and stick hair gel in it and try and make it do things that.
It didn't want to do and it wasn't going to do when I used to get very frustrated about that and then as you get older and wiser, you realize actually it looks fine and I quite I quite like it.
I don't get my haircut that often so it often gets a bit too long and messy for me and then when I can't put up with it any longer
I can't get it cut.
And how do you feel about the hairdresser, Do you like the experience, I don't mind it.
It's not, it's not something I really like doing, but I don't really mind it.
I don't have a problem with it.
And it does feel good to come out and it's a lot neater than it was when you went in Yeah, how long does a usual appointment take when you go to the hairdresser
It depends how busy it is, but, Yeah, if it's, if it's quiet, I can probably go in20, 30 minutes and its done.
Wow, what about you.
Well, I think my experience of the hairdresser is a little bit different.
If I get a haircut and a hair dye, so a hair dye is when you change the color, it can take about three hours, but I actually enjoy it.
I probably go to the hairdresser once every six months and when I go it's like a treat Okay you told us about the hairdressers, Georgie, do you often change your hairstyle?
Well, when I was at university, I once dyed my hair, not all of it, but half of it, pink and green, but the dye, the hair dye wasn't permanent.
It was.
Temporary, so the colour didn't stay, which was probably good for me.
I don't think I suited it, but recently, I actually have thought about growing my hair, so I want to Grow it, make it a bit longer.
And I want to stop dye it as well.
So in the last few years, I have been dyeing my hair a bit blondunder, but I was looking at some old photos of me when I had brown natural hair,
And I think I'd like to go back to it, Yeah, what about you, I don't think I'm going to change my hair.
I Do you think greenwood suit.
Phil, I think you would look great with.
Maybe maybe we should try that because my hair is changing its colour itself it's going grayer and grayer and grayer and every time I get my haircut more gray comes
Off well maybe green would be the way forward the other thing is there's there's less of it when I get my haircut I could see it's
Higher up and there's a bit going a little bit bald there but hopefully no one notices.
Let's recap the language we heard during the conversation.
If you dye your hair and that spt D Y E, then you use chemicals to change the colour.
Blonde hair is a light color, a bit like yellow.
Ger hair is a bit like orange.
If your hair is curly or wavy, It's not straight, It has curves.
And if you're bald, you don't have any hair on your head.
That's it for this episode.
Re easy EnglishWe'll be back next week with another conversation in easy English and don't forget to test what you've learned with the free worksheet on our
Website go toarningenglish.
Bye for.